Pratik Pingale

Pune. India

🖫 +919075715518 | @ pratikbpingale9075@gmail.com | 💣 proxzima.dev | 🗘 github.com/PROxZIMA | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/pratik-pingale

Personal Profile

I seek problems to solve them. I Love to learn whatever that will make the future. Highly versatile and adapt quickly to a changing environment. Passionate, and specialized in Front-End Web Development alongside modern frameworks like React/Django and other libraries. Open Source contributor and Competitive Programmer.

Professional Experience_____

Convin.ai Pune, India

Backend Engineer and Android Developer

Sept 2021 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated with a thirteen-person team to develop and integrate backend APIs using Django Rest Framework which improved
 and optimized data handling.
- Analyzed and performed speech-to-text conversion on customer call recording audios using Amazon Transcribe and Google Translate APIs along with AI based filters to recognize multilingual parts of speech.
- Build and deployed an organizational-level Android application with advanced functionalities like call recording and efficient background syncing for large audio files which aided a big management team of a renowned organization.
- Letter Of Recommendation ♂.
- Technical Skills: Python, Django REST framework, Android, Kotlin, AWS, PostgreSQL, Ubuntu Linux, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, and Presentation skills.

Organizational Experience _____

AISSMS COE Pune, India

Core Team Member Google Developer Student Club

Sept 2020 - Sept 2022

- Team leader of the Competitive Programming Team. Conducted many virtual and physical events for freshers and juniors.
- The events were based on Git, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Competitive Programming which helped them to understand the basic fundamentals and eventually get better at coding.
- Member of the Web Development Team. Contributed to the DSC AISSMSCOE ${\it z}$ official website.
- · Technical Skills: Python with Algorithms, Data Structures, Tailwind CSS, Firebase, Git.
- · Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

AISSMS COE Pune, India

Core Team Member Microsoft Student Club

July 2021 - Sept 2022

- Build a University Timetable Scheduler \(\mathbb{Z} \) model with a colleague, that works using a Genetic algorithm and is portable for scheduling scenarios may it be a schedule for school, employee timesheet, etc.
- Designed to be flexible to any case with low time complexity compared to the existing models which were only useful in specific scenarios.
- Build a Certificate App
 for easier certificate generation and distribution. This helped the college's Sports department to handle competitions and events related certificates.
- Technical Skills: Python with Genetic Algorithms, Django, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, CI & CD, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

Projects_____

DarkSpider ☑ Pune, India

AISSMS COE

Aug 2022 - Current

- Identification of Network Structures of the Dark Web by Exploring its Topological Properties by crawling and extracting onion web pages via the TOR Dark web network using a multi-threaded BFS crawler.
- · DarkSpider is a multi-threaded crawler and extractor for regular or onion web pages through the TOR network, written in Python.
- Technical Skills: Python with multi-threaded BFS crawler, TOR.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Leadership, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

Timetable Scheduler & Pune, India

• An intelligent timetable generator that generates a University timetable using a Genetic Algorithm.

- AISSMS COE Sept 2021 Jan 2022
- · The project uses Genetic Algorithm to satisfy the Hard & Soft constraints related to the Timetable schedule.
- Technical Skills: Python with Genetic Algorithms, Django.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Logical Thinking.

Museum Gallery & Pune, India

Personal Project May 2020 - Aug 2020

- A VR based Museum application made for enjoying museums from home.
- Technical Skills: Android with Java, Google VR SDK.

Twitter Sentiment Analysis &

Pune, India

Personal Project Apr 2022 - May 2022

- Twitter Sentiment analysis of tweets using vaderSentiment, CountVectorizer, and KMeans.
- Analyzing and cleaning texts using stop words removal, tokenization, stemming, and lemmatization.
- Technical Skills: Python with KMeans, Pandas, NumPy, seaborn, scikit-learn.

proxzima.dev 2 Pune, India

Personal Project May 2022 - Current

- · Highly customizable, easy-to-use, and minimal terminal styled website, powered by Next.js.
- · Technical Skills: TypeScript with React.js and Next.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Shell Scripting.

Education

AISSMS College of Engineering

Pune, India

B-Tech in Computer Engineering

Aug 2019 - Current

· Organizing and managing technical events.

9.38 SGPA

- Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Blockchain Technology, Computer and Security, Database Management Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Graphics, Discrete Mathematics
- Honours: Artificial Intelligence for Big Data Analytics, Machine Learning & Data Science, Statistics and Machine Learning, Data Science and Visualization

Pragnya Junior College

Pune, India

High School

Jul 2017 - May 2019

- Passed with Distinction
- Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

Skills

Programming Python (Numpy, Pandas, Jupyter, Django, Flask. etc.), C/C++, Kotlin, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript,

TypeScript(React.js), MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), ET_EX(Overleaf), Figma, Postman, Google Cloud, Firebase, Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Versatility, Adaptability, Multitasking, and Public Speaking.

Achievements

2020 **Winner**, Internal Hackathon for Smart India Hackathon (SIH)

2015 **Winner**, District level Karate Competition

India

Interests_

 $\label{linux} \textbf{Linux} \quad \text{Since 2020, I have been in love with Linux. Linux ricing $\ensuremath{\textbf{z}}$ is my hobby.}$

Anime I enjoy watching anime of a few specific genres like shonen and seinen.

Video Games I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my PS3.

Karate I started karate when I was 15. I have participated in a few state and national-level competitions. **Music** I enjoy almost all types of music but the genres I enjoy the most are aesthetic EDMs and electro.

Languages

English Professional proficiency

Hindi Native proficiency

Marathi Bilingual proficiency